<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>koon.dev</title><link>https://koon.dev/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on koon.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 13:14:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://koon.dev/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kaifu Lee, AI Superpowers</title><link>https://koon.dev/library/ai-superpowers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 13:14:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://koon.dev/library/ai-superpowers/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://koon.dev/book/ai-superpowers/cover.jpg" alt="AI Superpowers Cover">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Kaifu Lee&amp;rsquo;s 2018 book, &amp;ldquo;AI Superpowers, China, Silicon Valley, and the New World Order&amp;rdquo;, AI&amp;rsquo;s history, current developments, and future implications for both China and the US are all described in detail from someone with first hand experience in the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first half of the book, Lee discusses the history of AI in both countries. Lee believes it is important to clarify these details because as a Westerner, most information comes from media, as opposed to first hand experience, so there are many gaps in understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://koon.dev/book/ai-superpowers/alphago.jpg" alt="AlphaGo vs Lee Sedol">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chapter one discusses China&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Sputnik moment&amp;rdquo;, comparing the Soviet&amp;rsquo;s launch of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sputnik_1">Sputnik 1 satellite&lt;/a> as the catalyst for the Space Race, to the world&amp;rsquo;s best &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(game)">Go&lt;/a>, an ancient Chinese board game, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlphaGo_versus_Lee_Sedol">player&amp;rsquo;s defeat by an AI&lt;/a> as the event kickstarted China&amp;rsquo;s interest in AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second chapter describes China&amp;rsquo;s view from the Americans as a &amp;ldquo;copycat&amp;rdquo; country. Lee says that this view had some validity in the beginning of China&amp;rsquo;s internet age, but today, and especially in the age of AI, China has caught up and surpassed the US in many ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chapter three discusses the separate internet that has developed in China, comparing it to that of the US.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One example Lee brings up is the leapfrogging China did with two technologies. When personal computers first became popular, the average Chinese person could not afford to buy one for quite a while. That was until cheap mobile phones became popular, and suddenly almost all of China had access to the internet. This allowed China to leapfrog personal computers, right to cell phones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That had many effects on the economy but perhaps the biggest one was it allowed the Chinese to leapfrog another technology: credit cards. Lee describes how the Chinese had never adopted credit cards, opting for cash instead (which I found very interesting). Once everyone in China, at least in the big cities, had internet connected cell phones, all it takes is an application, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alipay">Alipay&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WeChat_Pay">WeChat Pay&lt;/a>, that would scan a QR code from the phone&amp;rsquo;s camera to make a payment. Almost all commerce in China is made through mobile payments, compared to just a fraction in the US.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lee briefly discusses the dangers posed by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_singularity">&amp;ldquo;the singularity&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> staying that still many decades away. He writes that the more relevant issue regarding AI will be job automation, and its effects on the economy and society.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>